[
    {
        "question":"\\text{surface tension(s)=?}",
        "answer":"s=\\frac{L}{L}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{for soup solution s=?}",
        "answer":"s=2s"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{force acts on ring due to S.T}",
        "answer":"mg\\:+\\:4\\pi rs"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{force acts on disk due to S.T}",
        "answer":"mg\\:+\\:2\\pi rs"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{force acts on anullar ring due to S.T}",
        "answer":"mg\\:+\\:2\\pi s(r_1+r_2)"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{force acts on rectrangular plate due to S.T}",
        "answer":"mg\\:+\\:2s(a+b)"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{force acts on wire or thin rod due to S.T}",
        "answer":"f = 2sl"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{surface energy(E)=?}",
        "answer":"E=SA"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{surface energy(E) for drop}",
        "answer":"E=s.4\\pi r^2"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{surface energy(E) for bubble}",
        "answer":"E=2\\times s.4\\pi r^2"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{surface energy(E) for soap bubble}",
        "answer":"E=2\\times 2s.4\\pi r^2"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{work done?}",
        "answer":"E=SA"
    },
    {
        "question":"cos(\\theta)\\;when\\;drop\\;is\\;droped\\;on\\;surface",
        "answer":"cos(\\theta)=\\frac{T_2-T_1}{T_3}"
    },
    {
        "question":"Δp\\;in\\;liquid\\;drop",
        "answer":"p_{concave}=p_{convex}+\\frac{2S}{R}\\;or\\;p_{inside}=p_{outside}+\\frac{2S}{R}"
    },
    {
        "question":"Δ p\\;in\\;soap\\;bubble",
        "answer":"p_{inside}=p_{outside}+\\frac{4S}{R}"
    },
    {
        "question":"NOTE: if 2 surface(bubble)\\--->Δ p=\\frac{4S}{R}.\\;and\\;if 1 surface(drop)\\--->Δ p=\\frac{2S}{R}",
        "answer":""
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{air bubble inside liquid a liqid}",
        "answer":"p_i=p_a+\\rho gh+\\frac{2s}{R}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{height in capillary rise}",
        "answer":"h=\\frac{2Scos(\\theta)}{r\\rho g}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{when 2 bubble collapse externally,R=?}",
        "answer":"R=\\frac{r_1r_2}{r_2-r_1}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{when 2 bubble collapse internally,R=?}",
        "answer":"R=\\frac{r_1r_2}{r_2+r_1}"
    },
    {
        "question":"\\text{force requires to seperate glass plates}",
        "answer":"F=\\frac{2SAcos(\\theta)}{d}"
    }
    
]
